Say me outside and I won't resist. I've
waited all this time.
I can't wait for this. I can't wait to
see this play out in real life.
This is how intelligence is made.
A new kind of factory,
generator of tokens, the building blocks
of AI.
Tokens have opened a new frontier,
turning data into knowledge, reason,
action.
They reveal patterns in complexity we
could never see.
Mirror our cities to keep us safe.
and lift us high
above them.
Tokens help robots learn from us,
work alongside us.
They go where we cannot.
lending us helping hands
and closing the gap between hope and
healing so that we breathe easier.
And the smallest hearts beat stronger.
Tokens are helping us break new ground
on a scale never attempted.
So we can reach star cloud one
separation confirmed to infinity
and beyond.
Together we take the next great leap
into a bright new future
built for all mankind.
And here in Taipei is where it all
begins.
Welcome to the stage Nvidia founder and
CEO Jensen Wong.
Welcome to GTC Taiwan.
So great to see all of you.
Very good to be home. I brought my
parents home. Where are my parents?
Everybody give round of applause to my
mom and dad.
And a round of applause
for our pregame show superstars. Ladies
and gentlemen,
look how adorable they are.
the superstars of Taiwan. Uh there are
so many of you here today. We are
broadcasting this right now to 70 other
watch parties across Taiwan.
70 different conferences are going at
the same time. Everybody is watching
this keynote. We have so much to tell
you and I have so many partners to
thank. It is incredible how large our
ecosystem in Taiwan has become. Most of
the time when people think about
ecosystem, they think about our software
stack. They think about the developer
ecosystem above the computing systems
that Nvidia builds. But NVIDIA's
ecosystem
spans all the way upstream to all of our
supply chain here in Taiwan where it all
begins and downstream all the way to
data centers and eventually to end
users. Today we're going to talk about
almost all of the ecosystem. There's so
many people to thank. I love my
ecosystem here. I mean, there are so
many companies here and some of my
favorite ecosystem partners.
That's right.
So many
Taiwan's rich ecosystem,
the richest ecosystem, the world's best
supply chain ecosystem. Unbelievable.
Well, thank you all for being here and
uh this year, this year our businesses
together are growing in incredibly. In
fact, somebody told me last night that
the annual GDP of Taiwan is going to
grow almost 10%.
Unbelievable. Well, we have a lot to
talk about. Let's get going. Two years
ago, when I was here, I started to talk
to you about how AI has moved from
generative AI and the other waves of AIs
that are coming. The next wave of AI was
agentic AI and today we can say that
agentic AI has arrived that useful AI
has arrived. Now what does this mean?
This is GitHub. This is of course one of
the first applications of Agentic AI is
software coding. One of the most
valuable professions incredibly large
ecosystem. 30 million 40 million
professional software developers.
probably another couple of hundred who
are students and enthusiasts and so on
so forth but say 30 40 million software
developers in the world code for a
living and this represents most of them.
This is GitHub. The pull request is when
they download software they modify it
and commit is when they push it back up.
Okay. And so if you could look at this
in 2023,
the number of commits was 300 million.
2024,
400 million. 2025,
500 million commits. In the first few
months, in the first few months of 2026,
it has nearly tripled. Now, what does
that mean?
30 million software developers
representing about $3 trillion
worth of GDP producing three that's what
they're paid $3 trillion worth of
salaries per year which is generating
economic growth for the rest of the
industries. Say a hundred trillion
dollars of the world's industries is
impacted
is generated by $3 billion worth of
salary. That $3 trillion, excuse me,
three trillion that $3 trillion worth of
salary is now producing nearly three
times as much output.
It's effectively a $9 trillion
productivity from $3 trillion of
salaries. Does that make any sense? The
difference is absolutely extraordinary.
This is the potential. This is the
promise of AI. The number of engineers,
software engineers is actually
increasing. People talk about AI
reducing jobs. Complete nonsense. It's
causing more software engineers to be
hired. And the reason for that is very
simple.
If you can hire a software engineer and
you could generate
$9 trillion worth of productive work,
why wouldn't you want to hire more
software engineers?
If that line was flat, then obviously
people will hire fewer software
engineers. But because the output is so
incredible, people want to hire more
software engineers. This is going to
show up in our economy somehow soon. And
so the first thing is useful AI has
arrived. Now, what does that mean from
the industry's perspective? From the
industry's perspective, that means that
tokens are now in extraordinary demand.
Because if you could do this, you're
going to want to produce more of it. And
because tokens are now profitable units,
tokens are now profitable units of
revenues. because it is now profitable.
The AI companies want to build a lot
more tokens, generate a lot more tokens,
build more AI factories, which is the
reason why compute demand here in Taiwan
has skyrocketed.
It is precisely the reason why all of
you are so busy and your businesses are
doing so well. In fact, that looks like
some of your stock price
The compute pattern has changed.
Everything has changed. So the first
idea is that useful AI has arrived. AI
is now a profit generator. AI is now a
GDP generator. Behind it is a whole new
kind of computing pattern. Not just a
large language model, but an agent.
Today almost everything we're going to
talk about is going to be based on this.
So let me take a quick moment and show
you what I'm talking about inside in
this is a this is an agent. It's an
agent application.
In the old days this would be
application.
This would be code and this would be
operating system.
application code running inside an
application inside an operating system.
Today it is agent which consists of a
large language model or many
sitting inside a harness and that
harness helps it orchestrates it to do
productive work. This is the input. When
that input comes, it has to understand,
observe, reason, act, use tools. Use
tools. That tool could be a spreadsheet,
web browser, a data processing engine,
database engine. For example,
this is orchestrated. This harness
orchestrate this routing of information
every single time it touches either
processing the context,
understanding what is happening,
reasoning about what to do, coming up
with a plan that you can act that it
acts on. That orchestration path is
orchestrated by some software. And so
this is fundamentally a agent. It deals
with short-term memory called working
memory, long-term memory just like we
do. We have long-term memory and so the
memory management system is incredibly
important. This entire system is called
an agent. The large language model is
used to do the thinking and the harness
connects everything together just like
an operating system. Okay. And so this
is the new computing model and this is
what an agent it could do incredible
things. This is the big breakthrough the
simultaneous conver the convergence of
large language models that are now able
to do a really good job thinking
reasoning planning using tools and the
fact that we have now these harnesses
that manages memory the orchestration
uses tools we can now do amazing things.
Let me give you some example. This is
this is a prompt. This is the prompt.
This is the code that is generated. And
this comes out.
This is the input.
This is the input. And that's the
output.
Do you guys What do you guys think? It's
pretty amazing, right?
We use cloud code here, but Codeexit
does an incredible job as well. Here's
another example.
This is the input. Create a GIF. Nvidia
gen green dots on black scatter form
Taiwan 101 building. Morph to GTC Taipei
to 2026. Morph to Nvidia I logo then
scatter and repeat. Right? So you saw
that that was the prompt. Here's the
next one. I lost my remote control
battery clip. It looks like this. Create
a CAD file. It uses a tool. create a CAD
file ready for 3D printing to create a
new new one. Make sense? This is now the
new computing pattern. Whereas we used
to launch an application,
click and type, we now replace that with
explaining to the AI what we want, our
intent and the AI generates the code or
uses tools and produce the necessary
output.
This is how computers are going to work
in the future. This is agentic AI. For
two years, we've been building towards
this and now it has arrived. Now, one of
the big breakthroughs, of course, is
tool use. A lot of people have said, you
know, Jensen, AI is coming. Agentic AI
is coming. Therefore, all of the
software companies are going to go out
of business. I said, it's exactly the
opposite because there are going to be
so many agents.
The world is no longer limited by the
number of people. Therefore,
those agents are going to use more tools
than ever.
This is actually an incredible time to
be a software company. But the software
has to be presented to the agent in a
way that the agent can use it. This is a
break big breakthrough. And in fact,
what we have done as you know what
Nvidia's treasure is is all of our CUDA
libraries. I call them CUDA X libraries.
This is Nvidia's treasure. Today, we're
able to now pres present these CUDA X
libraries to agents who can use it much
more effectively than even h humans. And
so this is a wonderful time for CUDA X
libraries. Let's take a look.
20 years ago, we built CUDA, a single
architecture for accelerated computing.
We reinvented computing. A thousand CUDA
X libraries help developers make
breakthroughs in every field of science
and engineering. CUDAX libraries are
tools for agents.
CU litho for computational lithography.
CUPT for decision optimization.
CDSS for direct sparse solvers.
AIQ for deep research across structured
and unstructured documents.
Aerial for AI RAM,
warp for differentiable physics,
parabrics for genomics.
At their foundation are algorithms and
they are beautiful.
Heat. Heat.
Heat up here.
Heat
up
here.
Heat up here.
A round of applause for math. Math is
beautiful.
The computing pattern, the computing
pattern of software is going to change.
In fact, let's come back to this. This
is the agent. It is the ultimate
disagregated
and distributed computing computing
model.
So many different computers are going to
be activated in order to process this
agent. The agent consists of model
harness,
tools and skills
and a runtime.
All of that is running at different
places in a data center.
You can think of the model as the brain,
the harness as the body,
the tools that it uses
working
in a runtime. Think of it as a workshop.
So this is a person, a worker working
with tools in a workshop. Of course,
this is being done at extraordinarily
large scales and each one of those steps
are running in a different part of the
computer. And you could see the large
language model is thinking,
context processing, observing,
understanding the environment,
reasoning, coming up with a plan, and
acting on the plan. Every single time
that happens, an entire rack of Grace
Blackwell MVLink72 is activated. It's
thinking with the large language model.
Whenever it uses a tool, a CPU use is
used. That tool could be a C compiler.
It could be Python. It could be
JavaScript or it could be accelerated
computing. Today's agents are rel
relatively simple users of tools.
Tomorrow they're going to be very
sophisticated users of tools, which is
the reason why the CUDA X libraries that
I showed you are going to be incredibly
popular with agents. They solve some of
the most important problems the world
knows. And all of our CUDA X libraries
are now now going to come with skills
that the AI could learn how to use. So
the CUDA X library some skills basically
a manual the AI reads it and go aha
that's how you use it.
The ability to use these libraries by
agents are going to be incredible. And
so the tools run on CPUs and GPUs and
large language models. The security
harness runs on CPUs and a security
processor called a DPU. Nvidia's blue
field. The orchestration of all this
runs on a CPU. This is the entire
harness and the CPU is orchestrating all
of the work. One of the hardest parts is
memory. You could just imagine the
working memory is called KV caching.
What to remember? Compaction. Not just
compression but how to retrieve. Do you
retrieve structured data? Do you
retrieve unstructured data? What is the
ontology? The relationship of all of
these different data to itself.
That entire processing is incredibly
complicated. The memory system, the
memory system of AIS is going to cause
the storage system to be completely
revolutionized.
As you can see, every aspect of this
computing
model, this computing pattern, this new
application called an agent is
fundamentally different than the way
that applications used to run. A whole
bunch of software sitting inside a
binary, sitting inside an operating
system. This is the reason this
disagregated,
this distributed, this heterogeneous
computing problem is precisely the
reason we built our next generation.
Vera Rubin. Vera Rubin is not one chip.
Vera Rubin is not a GPU only. It starts
with the GPU. But Vera Rubin is
incredible.
This entire thing is Vera Rubin
from end to end. It has GPUs Vera Rubin
MVLink72.
It is orchestrated by Vera CPUs that I'm
going to tell you more about the storage
systems revolutionary Vera along with
CX9 our software stack called DOA the
security processor that's inside so that
everything is encrypted at rest
in motion as well as in use
everything across this is secure because
the AI model is so precious this is the
reason Why this entire system obeys
confidential computing?
Each one of these systems would be a
complete revolution in itself. Vera
Rubin is the most ambitious endeavor in
the history of our company.
The whole company worked on Vera Rubin
across all 40,000 engineers. Not to
mention all of you. All of you
participated in the creation of this
entire system. Vera Rubin is really a
miracle and it's not just one chip. It
is so many.
Well, it's even beyond that. A long time
ago, Nvidia used to be a GPU company.
But over the years, we've evolved
to become a systems company. You're
looking here now for the most complex
system, most complex and groundup system
ever designed.
But ultimately our customers, our
partners don't want to buy computers.
They want to build AI factories. Which
is the reason why Nvidia has really
started to transform oursel yet again.
You could see so much of our technology
is now at the entire infrastructure
scale. Our partners are at
infrastructure scale. Power generators,
cooling systems, the grid providers.
So many industrial companies are now
part of our ecosystem because ultimately
we're trying to build an entire stack
just like GPUs, just like when we were
building Grace Blackwell MVLink 72, just
like now we are building a full stack
system so that our customers could build
amazing AI infrastructure. Let's take a
look.
>> The world is racing to build AI
factories. The largest infrastructure
buildout in human history. AI factories
are incredibly complex. Every layer,
chip, rack, network, power, cooling,
grid must be designed together from end
to end because compute is revenues.
NVIDIA DSX is the blueprint, a reference
design for building and operating AI
factories at maximum efficiency and
profitability.
It starts with DSX SIM. With the DSX SIM
Omniverse blueprint, partners design and
validate an NVIDIA Vera Rubin AI factory
before a single rack lands.
They plan the layout,
simulate the power and cooling,
design the network, validate every
integration, test every change in the
digital twin.
The factory powers on. DSXOSS takes over
and provisions, operates, monitors, and
remediates the infrastructure,
turning the installed systems into
trusted, multi-tenant, resilient, AI
ready capacity.
Today's AI factories overprovision power
by up to 40%. DSX Max LPS lets operators
safely deploy more GPUs inside the same
power budget, adding billions in annual
revenue.
Breakthrough hot liquid cooling at 45° C
uses less water and energy. More power
going to revenue generating compute.
Incredible
dynamic power allocation steers power
from rack to rack, recovering stranded
watts, sending them where work is
happening.
In rack power smoothing flattens peak
current spikes and power surges
throughout the factory. Teams of AI
agents work with DSX Max LPS,
continuously coordinating to balance
cooling and power to meet workload
demand.
DSX AI factories are flexible energy
assets that operate cooperatively with
the grid. DSX Flex reads realtime grid
signals and dynamically adjusts factory
power when the grid needs relief.
100 gawatts of AI factories will come
online before the end of the decade.
NVIDIA DSX AI factories run at highest
efficiency, produce the lowest cost
tokens, and make the grid stronger.
I've shown you ecosystem slides of the
past
where Nvidia's computing layers and
software and software and computing
stacks are integrated into other
people's platforms, third party
platforms and libraries that serves end
markets. That was a computing ecosystem.
This is an AI factory ecosystem. This is
way downstream of all of you. Upstream
of me is all of you and downstream of us
is this ecosystem. Because Nvidia
ultimately is not just building a GPU,
not just building a system. We're
helping customers build these AI
factories, these AI infrastructure that
is so immensely complex. Each one of
these at one gigawatt level started at
30 2030 billion dollars. It is at 5060
billion and soon it will be 80 hundred
billion per gigawatt.
$100 billion into an AI factory.
It must work the first time and it must
work right away. The cost of capital is
incredible. The complexity is
incredible. So as you see we used to
design a chip inside a computer
and then we simulated a system inside a
computer. Today you saw just now
everything was built in Omniverse.
I've been working with Omniverse with
all of you for a long time. This was the
dream come true so that we can build
these gigantic systems as large as the
world wants to build inside a digital
framework inside a digital simulator in
a digital world long before we build the
first break ground and put our money to
work. So this is our ecosystem our we
call it DSX.
RTX is for our GPU, DGX for our systems,
and now DSX basically infrastructure.
Because of the work that we do here
across this entire stack, including our
systems and software, it's the reason
why we could work with small companies
and enable them to be worldclass AI
clouds. Every one of these I'm about to
show you are small companies just
recently. And now Corewave is worth 50
60 70 billion dollars and growing
incredibly fast. Recently we worked with
Nibbius and again they're growing
incredibly fast. Each one of these
clouds have incredible customers. Cursor
the software coding company, Black
Mountain Labs, Image Generation, World
Labs, World Foundation model, Revolute,
the leading uh financial services AI
company, and Shopify. Here's another
one. This is Nscale and their customers
are British Telecom, Google. Google is
using one of our AI clouds, Thinking
Machines, a Frontier Labs company. Super
exciting. Here's Neighbor Cloud in
Korea, Bank of Korea, Hyundai.
So many incredible companies. Here's one
in in India, Yoda.
Incredible companies. Here's one uh
based in Singapore building in a
Australia together AI AI Singapore. This
is one in Indonesia. Each one of these
companies each one of these companies
are serving regional as well as global
customers. AI is going to run
everywhere. Every company will be
powered by it. Every region will build
it. Endosat here in in Indonesia here in
Taiwan. GMI
here in Taiwan. GMI. It's okay to clap.
So, incredible, incredible uh incredible
companies, incredible opportunity, but
all of them need several things. Of
course, they need the computing stack.
This entire stack underneath this is
what made Nvidia famous.
All of our hardware and software and
libraries, our connection into the
world's ecosystem of third party
developers makes it possible for anyone
to stand up an AI cloud. However, the AI
cloud is so complex now. This is the
software version. This is the computer
science version,
the money version,
the asset version is what I showed you
earlier. It's a giant factory. Having
this ability alone is not enough which
is the reason why Nvidia has become an
AI infrastructure company. Now doing
this well and becoming incredibly good
at dep at helping customers build AI
factories and deploying AI factories is
incredibly important. And the reason for
that is this. Compute is revenue now.
Compute is profit. the absence of
revenues and profit is loss. And so it's
really important to realize that this is
when this is an example of
an AI infrastructure coming online. It
could take it could be coming online
quickly. It could take a while. Its
throughput could be high. It could be
low. Its resilience and reliability
could be good or bad. And its lifetime
of usefulness could be long or short
because this represents
50 60 going to a hundred billion
dollars.
This curve matters greatly which is the
reason why Nvidia is such a great
partner working with us because of our
fully integrated capability. We didn't
just come up with a PowerPoint slide. We
created the entire infrastructure. We
connected everything together. We built
out billions and billions of it
ourselves to make sure that everything
works well. As a result of that, our
time, our time to first token, our time
to first token, our time to first
inference,
our time to training turned on is much
faster. Second, because our
throughput per watt, our tokens per watt
is utterly worldclass. And the reason
for that is because we integrate
everything. We design everything from
the ground up. We simulate the entire
system and we use extreme code design
just like I showed you just now with the
Vera Rubin rack. Everything was designed
in order to deliver on this incredible
throughput.
If your data center, if your factory has
one gigawatt,
it will not have more. One gawatt means
1 gawatt. That's all the power
generation you could do. If you have one
gawatt of power, then throughput per
watt is revenues because every token is
profitable. Every token is revenues.
This is the future.
Compute is revenues. Performance per
watt is your revenues. Choosing the
wrong architecture.
Just because the chips are cheaper
doesn't translate, doesn't make sense.
You need to make sure that your revenues
per watt, the more you buy, the more you
make.
And so tokens per wide.
And then lastly, very last oh second,
third is reliability.
If you ever get a chance to see these
data centers, there are so many moving
parts, millions of cables,
the ability for all of those computers
to work harmoniously,
reliably is extremely low. It is just
extremely difficult. We have now been
operating very large scale for a very
long time. That experience matters. That
difference meanantime between interrupts
extremely important. And then lastly,
this is very hard.
The lifetime of these systems, the
lifetime of these systems, the software
is changing all the time. Four years
ago, which is in the time of Hopper, AI
has completely changed.
Six years ago, this is the time frame of
Ampear, AI has completely changed.
We started out talking about CNN's,
here we are. Then we talked about
transformers and then we talked about
mixture of experts. Now we're talking
about agentic systems.
Every single generation, every single
few months, the software industry is
coming up with new technology. If your
architecture
is not flexible, if your ecosystem is
not rich, then this curve cannot be
long. You cannot predict how long your
system can last. I can. Nvidia systems
is all over the world. Software
developers start with Nvidia CUDA and by
definition therefore the life, the
ecosystem,
the useful asset is going to be much
longer. The difference is essentially
cost. You could think of it as revenues,
but the other side of revenues is cost.
If the life of the asset is long, the
TCO is low.
This is the difference. This is what it
looks like when compute.
The more you buy, the more you make.
Now, all of you are experiencing this
with me. Isn't that right?
>> All of your demand, your factories are
working so hard, your people are working
so hard all across Taiwan because
everybody wants to make money. They
realize that AI, useful AI is here.
Profitable AI is here. Compute demand is
incredibly high and compute demand is
the constraint. And so let's go work
super super hard and help the world
stand up AI factories everywhere. This
is why it's so important. I'm so happy
here I am standing in front of you. Vera
Rubin is in full production.
Vera Rubin is in full production.
it. The um the supply chain we created
for Vera Rubin is twice as large as
Grace Blackwell.
Not Yeah, it's incredible. And And what
used to take two hours to assemble one
Grace Blackwell rack now only takes 5
minutes. So not only is the capacity
higher, the throughput is a lot faster
and we need it all to support the
demand.
This ecosystem is extraordinary.
Millions of square feet has been put
online to support Grace Blackwell and
preparing now ramping up now Vera Rubin.
I want to thank all of you. Vera Rubin
is now in full production. Thank you.
Let's take a look.
Large language models generate answers.
Now AI agents can do work. But
processing agentic AI is a whole
different kind of problem. Agents
observe, reason, plan, use tools. They
manage massive context, juggling working
memory and long-term memory. They spin
up sub aents, specialists on demand.
NVIDIA Vera Rubin is a multi-rackck pod
scale system built to process Agentic AI
and is now in full production. The
manufacturing, automation and
orchestration across the supply chain, a
miracle to witness. Our journey started
when we launched the first AI
supercomputer, Nvidia DGX1.
Over the next decade, we pushed every
chip and system to the limit. From
Pascal and the first MVLink to Grace
Blackwell, the first rack scale AI
supercomputer. And now, Vera Rubin, the
first multirack pod scale supercomputer
built for the agentic age. It starts at
TSMC. The seven new chips that make up
Vera Rubin take shape through hundreds
of processing steps. 3 nanometer
process, co-wr
packaging, HBM4 memory from Micron, SKH
Highix and Samsung. The Vera Rubin
compute board. 6 trillion transistors
with over 18,000 components on one
board. Vera Rubin NVL72 does the
thinking, prompt and context
understanding, reasoning, and planning.
Next, a new modular comput streamlined
with a new PCB midplane design, super
chips, connect X9 super nicks, and
Bluefield 4 DPUs, all made in place with
no cables for resiliency at AI factory
scale, 18 compute trays, nine hot
swappable NVLink switch trays, new high
efficiency manifolds, liquid cooled buzz
bars carrying over 5,000 amps, the
equivalent of 20 electric cars at full
acceleration. Together, 1.3 million
components formed this third generation
MGX rack design. Congratulations to
Microsoft for their operational Vera
Rubin MVL72 engineering rack.
Congratulations to Dell and Coreweave as
well for standing up their Vera Rubin
MVL72 engineering rack. Then the Vera
CPU rack. 256 CPUs in a single liquid
cooled rack. Orchestrating the models,
shuffling memory, launching tools. At
Foxcon and Quanta, Gro 3 LPX takes
shape. 256 Gro 3 LUS across 16 trays, 40
pabytes per second of SRAMM bandwidth
for ultra low latency.
While MVL72 generates tokens at the
highest throughput, Grock LPX generates
them at the lowest latency.
Vera Bluefield 4 STX where AI keeps its
memory. Storage processing accelerated
by Bluefield 4 connecting memory,
storage, and insilicon security.
and NVIDIA Spectrum X Ethernet photonix.
The world's first Ethernet switch with
200 gigabit co-packaged optics. TSMC's
coupe process chip scale packaging and
ultra highowered laser dies on indium
phosphide.
Vera Rubin five connected rack scale
systems. A supercomput for AI agents.
150 supply chain partners across Taiwan.
Millions of square feet of factory
floor, hundreds of sites, chips,
packages, systems, and data centers
pushed to the limits of size, power, and
scale. This is what we call extreme code
design. We did this with Taiwan.
Together, we reinvented computing for
the age of AI. Taiwan was with us at the
beginning and here today as we bring
Vera Rubin to the world. Thank you,
Taiwan.
Ladies and gentlemen, Vera Rubin.
Vera Rubin
was not just built for AI. AI. Vera
Rubin was not built just to run AI. Vera
Rubin was built to run agents. This is
an agentic system. Imagine the
complexity. Which is the reason why
agents is the last computer science
breakthrough. It has taken this many
years for agents to realize its
potential and become useful. It stands
to reason that the computer that runs it
is the most advanced in the world. This
is Vera Rubin. Let's take a look. Can we
bring out Vera Rubin, please?
And Janine, do we have the Do we have
the racks, the systems?
It looks heavy.
This is This is Vera Rubin. Vera Rubin
MVLink 72.
This is the Gro LPX. At the next GTC,
I'm going to talk to you about a lot
more of this today. We have so much to
talk to you about. This is Vera CPU
rack. 256 CPUs, all liquid cooled. Let
me tell you about Vera in just a moment.
This is the Vera Bluefield storage
processing system and also security
system. And of course, this is our
Melanox networking. the world's first
CPO.
This is Vera Rubin. Incredible
technology all coming together. Now,
when we built when we built Hopper, we
built Hopper as you know for
pre-training.
Pre-training was the most important
application, the most important workload
we were working on at the time. Then
when we worked on Grace Blackwell,
everybody said, "Jensen, you know,
Nvidia is really good at pre-training.
Inference is so easy. Do you remember
that? People used to say inference is so
easy. We could do that too. But as you
know, inference equals money. And the mo
models are so complicated. And to do it
at incredibly high response time, fast
interactivity and high throughput at the
same time is incredibly hard. Which is
the reason why we created MVLink 72.
Today, Nvidia's token cost is the lowest
in the world. Not by 10%, by X factors,
orders of magnitude.
All because we did extreme code design.
All because we understood the computing
model, the computing pattern of
inference and we were able to create
MVLink 72. Now with Vera Rubin, it is
beyond inference. It is now inference in
an agent agentic system. This is Vera
Rubin. No cables,
no hoses, no fans.
What used to take the last time when I
showed this to you, we had cables
everywhere.
The cables were amazing to look at. But
now there's a PCB in the middle which
connects both sides. What used to take
two hours now takes 5 minutes. The
reliability and the resilience of Vera
Rubin is going to be off the charts.
This is our Vera CPU tray. The most
advanced CPUs that has ever been built.
I'm going to show you that in just a
second. And this is our storage tray.
Two Vera CPUs,
four CX9. incredible amounts of
software.
This is our new
LPX LPU30,
the Gro system designed for very low
latency inference. The throughput is
delivered by Vera Rubin and extended
with MVLink 72. If you want to extend
that even further, you can have Gro
LPUs. Here we have the Vera Rubin MVLink
the switch tray. This is the switches in
the middle and this is revolutionary
because of Vera Rubin's because of
MVLink72 and the MVLink switches that we
created and invented and this is our
Ethernet switches for scale out. What's
amazing is we introduced these two
systems for Grace Blackwell. These two
systems were created for Grace Blackwell
and today Nvidia is the largest
networking company in the world. I'm so
proud of the networking team. This is
such an incredible enabler for
everything that we do. I'm going to now
talk to you about the next major
industry we're going to be part of.
Thank you, Janine.
Thank you.
I think there are 2,000 people back
there pulling that.
Okay, let's talk about CPUs.
Vera CPUs. CPUs built for the age of AI.
All of the CPUs until now
were created for people. We were the
users.
We were the users, we were the renters.
The way we use CPUs, we live in a world
counted by seconds.
The way we rent CPUs in the cloud, each
one of them more you can more CPU cores
you have, the more you can rent. the
economics of the old the use case of the
old CPU and the economics of the old CPU
fundamentally different than agents.
Agents
are impatient. They don't live in a
world that is in seconds. They live in a
world that's in nanoseconds.
When it uses a tool, it wants the
response time to be as fast as possible.
When it access database, it has to come
back as soon as possible. Every moment
that the agent is waiting
keeps it from going to the next step,
the next step, the next step. It is
vital that we make the CPUs as low
latency as possible, as interactive as
possible. So we created Vera CPU for the
age of AI. Now inside our system, it's
used for three different ways. The first
way of course is Vera Rubin
for thinking and inside the Vera Rubin
rack there are already two CPUs. As you
know we are building and selling
millions of Vera Rubins. We have sold
millions of Grace Blackwells. Nvidia
already is one of the largest CPU makers
in the world. Vera in the Vera Rubin
rack are two CPUs. One for orchestrating
and managing the GPUs,
managing the KV cache,
dealing with all of the software that
runs in the rack. We also have the grace
blue field that is used for security and
isolation.
The Vera compute is used for the
harness, the orchestration of the AI
models, tool use, accessing the
database. And the data servers are right
here, Vera Bluefield, the fastest
storage, fastest storage servers, the
fastest storage system the world has
ever made. And the reason why this is so
vital is because agents are accessing
memory, accessing memory so incredibly
fast. These systems, the storage server
and the CPUs are now the critical path
of the most expensive part of the data
center. This is the most expensive for a
good reason.
The economics, the economics of the AI
factory is tokens
and the tokens are created here. And so
of course you want to manufacture and
generate as many tokens as possible.
This is where you put all of your
economics and this has to not be in the
way. And so Vera CPU has great pressure
on the Vera on the CPU architecture
which is the reason why we built a brand
new architecture from the ground up. A
CPU the world has never seen before. We
call it Vera.
This is CPU
for agents.
All the CPUs of the past we built for
humans. This CPU is built for agents.
Well, there are four things to keep in
mind. The four takeaways. The first
takeaway is that the instructions per
clock of Vera has to be incredibly good
because we need the latency to be short.
We need the processing time.
Singlethreaded performance, not
throughput. Singlethreaded performance
has to be world class. Absolutely the
best singlethreaded performance. Which
is the reason why the IPC the
instructions per clock of Vera is so
high. It's the highest in the world. 10
instructions fetched, decoded, and
executed per clock. Number one. Number
two,
the bandwidth necessary to move data in
and out for the CPU has to be utterly
world class. The second thing is
bandwidth per core. The third is just
bandwidth period. We're moving. Remember
I said earlier agentic systems is
fundamentally disagregated and
distributed disagregated and
distributed. When computing is
disagregated and distributed networking
becomes the problem. Therefore, we have
to move the data around as fast as
possible between the CPU cores and
between the CPU and the storage, the CPU
and the GPU.
The bandwidth around the system and
inside the CPU core has to be utterly
world class.
This is the first CPU that's been built
a long time that is literally at retical
limits with a fabric that connects all
of the CPU cores. That is speed of light
3.6 terabytes per second.
No chiplet taxs, no chip boundary
crossings because we need to have
everything because the CPU cores are
talking to each other with extremely
high bandwidth. They're not rented core
per core per core. They're all working
together. The cross-sectional bandwidth
of Vera is off the charts. It's the
first one to be PCI Express Gen 6. It is
also the first one to have LPDDR DDR5
with 1.2 terabytes per second. Three
times two to three times the bandwidth
of the highest performance CPUs on the
outside, three times the bandwidth on
the inside. The bandwidth per core and
the bandwidth period is world class. Now
remember I showed you earlier.
The number of CPU cores, the number of
CPUs is going to be quite high and the
reason for that is very simple.
We created CPUs
for humans in the past and humans there
are only 1 billion of us.
There will be billions of agents and
these agents are going to be using the
CPUs with very little patience.
because the cost of the GPU they sit
next to is too high and therefore
too valuable, too precious. Therefore,
these CPUs are going to be both
performant,
but they also have to be extremely
energy efficient so that we can cram as
much CPU as we can into the factory
without taking away power from the token
generation which we know is how we make
money. These four properties,
instructions per clock or single
threaded performance,
bandwidth per core,
the total bandwidth around the chip and
inside the chip and energy efficiency
defines Vera. It is absolutely world
class. When you compare it to the
highest performance x86, it is just off
the charts. When you compare it in real
singlethreaded performance, real
performance, it's off the charts.
It is incredible to be able to deliver
5% improvement on CPUs. It is incredible
to be able to deliver 10%. But this kind
of performance speed up is just unheard
of.
This is Nvidia Vera.
What do you think?
Let's take a look.
>> Aentic AI changes the role of the CPU.
The CPU is now the conductor and the GPU
is the orchestra. Traditional CPUs were
built for a different era. Maximizing
cores per socket. Slice them up,
virtualize, rent by the hour. In the age
of agents, the CPU is now a bottleneck
to GPU utilization. directly affecting
token throughput, latency, and user
experience.
NVIDIA Vera is the CPU built for the
Agentic loop, combining NVIDIA's custom
data center CPU core with the scalable
coherency fabric for the right balance
of performance cores and bandwidth to
maximize AI factory output. At the heart
of Vera is the NVIDIA Olympus core built
for modern data center workloads,
branchheavy Python runtimes, tool calls,
and sandbox code execution. Each core is
tuned for throughput. A neural branch
predictor evaluating two taken branches
per cycle. A 10 wide decode engine
brings in more work each cycle. A large
out-of- orderer engine keeps
instructions moving. Advanced
prefetchers with a novel graph engine
anticipating the next data path. But
fast cores only matter when data arrives
correctly and on time. Vera is the first
CPU to use LPDDR5X memory while
correcting multiple errors
simultaneously without compromising
bandwidth. Vera achieves 40% lower peak
memory latency versus x86,
keeping cores fed on time through
retrieval, analytics, and sandbox
execution. NVIDIA's second generation
scalable coherency fabric unifies all 88
Olympus cores on a monolithic mesh with
separate dies for memory and IO. cores
are not split across chiplets, enabling
50% faster core to core communication
than traditional CPUs. And memory
coherent NVLink chip to chip connects
GPUs directly to the fabric. Beyond
GPUs, NVLink chip to chip can scale Vera
up to multiple sockets, enabling massive
bandwidth between CPUs. Vera delivers
1.8 Eight times the agentic sandbox
performance of x86 CPUs. Standalone Vera
racks run agent sandboxes, tools, code,
and data pipelines. Tightly coupled to
Reuben GPUs, Vera keeps accelerated
workflows moving. Nvidia Vera Bluefield
4 STX powers context memory and AI
storage,
compute, networking, storage. Vera is
the CPU for the age of agents.
This is going to be our new major growth
driver. The reviews are already coming
out and it's pretty good.
That's pretty good stuff.
Now remember,
Grace and Vera
are also the most highly qualified
CPUs in the world of AI because every
single data center, every single cloud,
every single enterprise, every company
that works with Nvidia on AI has already
qualified
Grace. The entire software stack has
already been optimized for grace. Every
company will be qualifying Vera.
Vera will be the most optimized agentic
CPU in the world simply because it's
going to go with Vera Rubin simply
because we made the the big hard switch.
In fact, during Grace Blackwell
transition, the biggest risk was going
from external CPU x86 into Grace
Blackwell.
That transition was extremely dangerous,
but we did it with incredible execution.
Now Grace is literally synonymous with
Grace Blackwell. When people say
Blackwell, they say Grace Blackwell
because it is utterly now everywhere.
Every company's software stack has been
optimized for it. Everybody's security
stack has been optimized for it. And now
here comes Vera. I'm super excited about
that. Now look at some of the
performance numbers.
Speed up says one thing. It is extremely
hard to speed up SQL.
SQL the most famous
domainspecific language DSL that has
ever been created. Before SQL, you know,
before CUDA, there was SQL. Before
OpenGL, there was SQL invented by IBM.
Today, it is the structured database
engine of the planet. Everybody uses
SQL. This is SQL running three times
faster. Not 10% faster, not 25% faster,
10 times f three times faster.
Incredible. This is
real time. The next one is real time
stream processing. Remember, your AI is
going to be not just reading documents.
Your AI is going to be watching for
telemetry, especially inside a factory,
inside a stock exchange.
You're going to be looking for telemetry
continuously. The burst of data that's
coming in goes into a CPU. This is Vera
CPU running real time stream processing
for New York Stock Exchange. Lynn
Martin, the president of New York Stock
Exchange, has been so gracious to
partner with us. This system is run all
over the world in real time real time
stream processing vera CPU six times all
because of the bandwidth the single
single threaded instruction execution
the bandwidth inside between the cores
the bandwidth outside vera is completely
revolutionary
that's vera
you know X factors is something you you
talk about when you're talking about
GPUs. It is quite rare that somebody
talks about X factors on real workload
real workload that is associated with
CPU. So I'm so proud of the team. You
guys did such a great job. We have an
extraordinary road map coming.
But what's really exciting is almost
everybody is supporting Vera. They're as
excited as we are. This is Vera opening
up. It's opened up a brand new market.
Agents, agents is a new workload. We
built CPUs for humans in the past. We
need CPUs for agents. Agentic systems,
their properties are different. Why
would the old CPUs be the same? We are
building millions and millions of
errors. Millions of errors. and to go to
market with us. Taiwan's ODMs and
computer makers, all the OEMs, and you
could see the early adopters.
The early adopters are the agentic
companies. This is the beginning of a
new market, a market that never existed
before. It's not going to take away from
the old markets, but this is a new
market.
CPU for agents. And this will this c
this market will surely be larger than
the last and the reason for that is
because there'll be a lot more agents
than there are people and then there the
agents are very impatient. So Nvidia
Vera CPU thank you.
This is the most important slide really.
This is the takeaway. The takeaway here
is that this is the application pattern.
This is the computing pattern of the
next decade.
Agents, harnesses
orchestrating large language models.
Every company will run it. Every company
will be an agent company. Every company
will have agents running inside.
Every company will see that agents will
need its own operating system. Every
company's asking us how do we run agents
safely? How do we build agents for our
own workloads? And so we have the NVIDIA
agent toolkit for enterprise AI. You've
seen me build this in plain sight.
Almost everything that Nvidia does, as
you know, at every GTC, if you go back
and look at my GTC five years ago or 10
years ago, you will see today
this you've seen me talking about for
several years now because we've been
building for this moment. There are four
things that companies need in order to
build agents as a service or build
agents to operate.
The first thing you need is you need
models. Of course, large language
models, the smarter the better, the
cheaper the better, the faster the
better. The second is you need a harness
to orchestrate the whole thing. The
third, these a these models want to use
tools and these tools come with its
skills and I showed you CUDA X
libraries. Those are going to be amazing
tools for the agents in the future. And
then lastly, you need a runtime. You
need the operating system that holds it
all together. This is the Nvidia toolkit
for agents. It includes
it includes
models that you can modify. NVIDIA's
worldclass open models. And I want to
show you more. You can run agents from
anybody. You could run uh CL code
incredible agent codeex incredible
agent. You could run it inside this
harness called open shell which will be
highly secure for your inside the
enterprise. The shell protects the agent
keeps it grounded in security policies.
Privacy is protected. Its rights and
privileges are given its identity
protected. And so this open shell is
being adopted all over the world. Nvidia
open shell is open source. You're going
to see so many companies adopt it. Red
Hat, Canonical, Microsoft, it's going to
be adopted everywhere. This is an
important this is the runtime and this
runtime is fully optimized for the
Nvidia AI platform which is everywhere.
So you can run open shell in any cloud
on prem and even on device. So you have
you have now tools and libraries that
they can use. You have models that you
can modify or use asis or you have
agents. This would be open claw Hermes
another incredible another incredible uh
harness. These agent agentic harnesses
can now run on prem or for you anywhere.
Okay. So four things and this represents
the operating system of the modern
enterprise. Now how do we use this? One
of my favorite use cases of agents
is chip designers. It is the single most
important thing that Nvidia does. And so
of course we have to partner with
cadence to build super agent a chip
design super agent. It is orchestrated
by codecs or clock code. It has RTL and
architecture di diagrams or schematics
or uh specifications as input and
whatever you need to fix. And together
we created some super agents
that are optimized for the NVIDIA
runtime with Neotron. And let's take a
look. It's really incredible.
Cadence and Nvidia are partnering to
build chip design agents.
Hundreds of thousands of NVIDIA chips
come together to make the AI factories
that power the world's frontier AI
models. Designing these chips and the
systems they run in is one of the
hardest engineering challenges.
Trillions of transistors,
three-dimensional circuits, microscopic
scale. Every gate, every wire
synchronized to picos seconds must work
in perfect harmony with no margin for
error. Physical prototypes are too slow
and too costly. So engineers work in the
digital realm. Each chip begins as a set
of architectural specifications, then
translated into RTL, the language of
chip design. RTL must be verified in
simulation. A single bug can delay a
chip by months. At NVIDIA, thousands of
engineers, billions of compute hours per
year, millions of tests written, run,
and debugged. A cycle that takes teams
weeks. To compress this cycle, Cadence
and NVIDIA built a design verification
agent. Codeex orchestrates the process.
Cadence chipstack launches the RTL
verification loop powered by Neatron and
secured by Nvidia OpenShell. Calling on
expert sub agents in RTL generation,
testbench creation, regression testing
and debug, the system drives itself. The
chipstack agents run hundreds of
simulations with Cadence Excelium.
Formal verification with Jasper. Design
flaws revealed. Bugs in the code fixed.
What once took weeks now takes hours.
Verification cycles over 40 times
faster. Together, Nvidia and Cadence are
reinventing chip design with AI agents.
From weeks, from weeks to hours, from
weeks to hours, from weeks to hours,
Nvidia has thousands of chip designers.
We are going to hire hundreds of
thousands of cadence super agents that
work with us so that we can accelerate
our company so that we can be even more
ambitious, create even more amazing
things, run even faster. You saw earlier
that the toolkit with models, harness,
tools. The tools in this case are
cadence simulators and verifiers, formal
verification systems. It is the reason
why we're working with Cadence so hard
to accelerate all of their tools on CUDA
because the agents are impatient. The
agents want the answer immediately. And
so models,
harnesses,
accelerated CUDA, accelerated libraries
and tools, and then the runtime. What
you saw just now is all of that coming
together. Now, one of the things that it
starts with is a great model that
Cadence could modify and tune to be
expert at the Cadence workflow at the
Cadence expertise so that they could
create super agents that are proprietary
to Cadence with their proprietary
knowledge.
They have to start with an excellent
model. We call it Neotron. NVIDIA is
dedicated to build open models for the
world so that all of you, all of us
could create our own agents. Today,
we're announcing
the Neotron
3 Ultra.
Yep. Our next open model, and it is
smart.
The Neotron
models not only give you the model, we
give you all the data that we use to
train the model. And because we have a
coalition of incredible partners, you
can see all of our partners down here.
We work together, contribute data to
each other. Neotron is trained on one of
the largest suites of longunning
reasoning models, longunning tool task
solving tool using data sets in the
world because of all of our great
partnerships. All of this from the
model, the training script and the data
made completely available to you. This
is open models at its best. the best
open model system policies in the world.
Simple goal is so that you can take all
of it, add to it, make it even better,
make it yours. Neotron 3 Ultra is five
times faster.
This is the world's first model based on
a hybrid architecture of SSM state space
models with mixture of experts. The
architecture is incredibly fast. We made
a fast so that you could think fast.
When you think fast, you could think
longer at the same cost. So five times
faster. It is also
30% cheaper. 30% lower cost to run in
total flops and total inference time
than even the most cost effective in the
world. We're comparing against the
world's best open models. Frontier
Smart,
five times faster, 30 30% cheaper,
completely open. We're completely
dedicated to this. This is now Neotron
3. We're currently working on Neotron 4.
So this entire toolkit from models,
harnesses,
tools and skills and runtimes is the
reason why every enterprise company in
the world has the ability now to create
their own agents just like Cadence did
with their super agents. And we're
working with so many companies, Cadence
and Crowdstrike and Disso and Palunteer,
SAP and Service Now. People were always
said Jensen the agents are going to
disrupt these markets. I said completely
opposite and you can now see it. Agents
is going to create the largest
opportunity ever for my partners and
friends. And we have the Nemo the the
NVIDIA agentic toolkit for enterprise AI
to help them.
So there you go.
First Vera Rubin in full production. Two
Vera CPU CPU built for a new generation
for agents. And three, Nvidia's
enterprise AI toolkits so that every
enterprise and every enterprise software
company can build agents.
My relationship with you started here.
And many of you, many of you, many of my
friends and partners here in Taiwan,
your companies started here.
This is in a lot of ways the beginning
of the modern computer industry. 40
years now, Nvidia is 33 years old. The
PC industry was already starting to get
the P Windows one and Windows 2 and
Apple one and Apple 2.
By the time that we came along, Windows
3.1 was the PC. And as you know, Windows
95 made PC personal. It took PC from
enterprises companies and made it into a
consumer electronics device. Everybody
should have one and everybody does. This
is the beginning. This computing
platform did several things incredibly
smart.
Windows was not just disagregated. As
you know, Windows was properly
abstracted. It was architected just
right. systems biosis,
open chipsets,
the operating system with drivers,
drivers that could be connected and
installed at runtime
and an abstraction layer with a
multimedia API that was that opened up
the PC to what we all know today. Each
one of these elements were essential in
making the PC so popular.
40 years later,
Microsoft and Nvidia are going to
reinvent the PC.
This is going to be the new PC. Now,
tomorrow night, tomorrow night, I think
it's tomorrow night our time, but I'm
going to be with Satia where we're going
to talk a lot more about the work that
we're doing together. Microsoft Nvidia
over the last three years. It took this
long to completely reinvent how the PC
is going to work so that we could be
ready for this moment. As I mentioned
earlier, that compute pattern called the
agent is going to run in AI clouds. It's
going to run inside enterprises. It is
also going to run on your PC.
What's going to happen to that PC when
it has an autonomous agent? An agent
that's helping you, that understands
you. You could talk to it. It could look
at you. You could
ask it to read files, go help you do
some research. It could do a lot more
that I'll show you. But the new
operating system is, of course, the old
operating system plus large language
models. Large language models in a lot
of ways is the modern version of
DirectX.
It has of course input and output,
understands prompts, it understands
computer vision, it can generate video,
it can generate sounds. It is the modern
extension, the intelligence extension of
the PC, of a computer.
On top of that, the application as I
mentioned before is going to be replaced
by now an agentic runtime and that is
the modern application an agent. Let's
now take a look at what it can do.
It started with a spark,
an idea to reimagine the PC for the
first time in 40 years for the age of
AI. What becomes of our personal
computer in a world of agents?
Agents running natively, connected to
models, local or in the cloud. Our
personal AI, sandboxed for security,
running continuously, getting work done.
The chips and the OS must evolve.
Introducing RTX Spark. Everything we've
learned over 33 years distilled into one
chip.
Blackwell RTX GPU with 6,144
CUDA cores. One pedaflop of AI
performance. A custom 20 core Grace CPU
built in partnership with MediaTek.
Fused by MVLink.
128 GB of unified memory. TSMC3
nanometer process, 70 billion
transistors,
and in close collaboration with
Microsoft, a Windows platform for
agents.
We're reinventing the personal computer,
for creating,
for gaming,
for agents.
This is the dawn of a new personal
computing revolution
and it starts with NVIDIA RTX Spark.
>> Here it is.
Of course, I got to show you the most
beautiful part, which is video games.
It is. It's also the closest to our
heart. This is Forza. This is 007, by
the way. The new 007 game. I'm looking
forward to playing it. I look a little
bit like him.
Ladies and gentlemen, Nvidia's RTX Spark
laptops. Now,
thank you.
I have too many things in my pocket.
Okay. All right. This is the most
amazing chip the world has ever built.
This is the N1X that we built in
partnership with MediaTek. I think I saw
I saw Rick earlier. This is N1X. This is
a beautiful chip. This is this is a a
chip that frankly would take 33 years to
build. And the reason for that is
because 100% of Nvidia software stack
runs here. If you want to run uh uh
digital biology, no problem. If you want
to do seismic processing, no problem.
You want astrophysics, no problem.
Everything associated with CUDA, all the
physics, all the biology, all the
genomics, all the AI, no problem. All
the computer graphics, no problem. Every
single application Nvidia has ever
created and every single application
that Windows has ever run,
Microsoft and Nvidia meticulously
optimized everything so that this
computer literally runs everything the
world has ever created. Plus,
it now runs agents. An incredible
computer. I'm so proud of it.
Okay.
Now, I want you to keep that in mind in
the next video. I just I'm going to show
you. Just imagine everything here is
going to run on your PC. Now that
computer could have a local Neotron 3
Ultra model or Neotron 3 supermodel or
it could have a cloud code or codeex or
some other model in the cloud or
something on the network and it's going
to it's going to work and do something
amazing. Let's play it.
>> Every house starts as an idea. Getting
from idea to design takes a myriad of
tools, expertise, and a lot of time.
Now, an agent running locally on RTX
Spark can help me design a house using
the tools on my laptop with an open
shell sandbox running the Hermes harness
connected to Claude Sonnet in the cloud.
I select the site, share my concept
sketches and mood board of styles to
inspire my design and the prompt, a text
description of the requirements
and the design intent.
My agent goes to work using the tools on
my laptop. It opens Rhino and starts
modeling the site, shaping terrain,
setbacks, and the building envelope.
Then it proposes building forms
optimized for cost, comfort, and
quality.
With the form defined, my agent
generates the interior layout. Walls,
circulation, rooms begin to take shape.
I jump in whenever I want to adjust to
change.
Doors, windows, and structural elements
are placed automatically. My agent
detects its own mistakes and fixes them.
When I approve, the agent exports the
model from Rhino into Blender. Materials
and object properties transfer with the
design context intact.
I fine-tune the materials, get the look
just right. Then I pick the shots.
Blender renders the house. My agent
using generative AI with the Flux 2
model makes them photoreal. Multiple
viewpoints, lighting conditions. What
was once a complex workflow is now
guided and simplified by my agent.
Working with on RTX Spark design at the
speed of imagination.
PC in the world of agents. The
developers are so excited about it. This
is an incredible computer. All of the
acceleration, all the software
capabilities associated with it, working
with every developer to make it
incredible for all of you. The next one,
Adobe, incredible tool suite of course
used by tens of millions of people
around the world. They have
re-engineered
the architecture, the core of Adobe,
Photoshop, and Premiere, and they're
going to release it for RTX Spark. It is
twice as fast. It's already fast. Now
it's going to be twice as fast. And it
it's also designed to be agentfriendly
with its MCP server. It can now interact
with agents on your laptop.
The number of customers, the number of
partners that are so excited to bring
RTX RTX Spark to the market is just
incredible. You know, this is the first
across the lineup of PC reinvention for
40 years. And I'm just so happy that all
of you and the ecosystem around the
world has joined us. This is basically
everybody. Everybody will support RTX
Spark and will be building incredibly
smart and powerful and beautiful laptops
with all of us. Thank you very much.
But that's not all. That's not all.
RTX Spark is a reinvention of laptop.
But in fact, Microsoft Nvidia is
reinventing all of PC. And today, we're
announcing a whole new line.
Three revolutionary Windows machines
covering desktop, laptop, and
workstations. All 100% Windows
compatible, 100% CUDA, 100% Nvidia AI
tensor core. Everything that runs that
you see that runs on Nvidia in all these
different platforms around the world
runs here.
This is the first completely
re-engineered, reinvented line of PCs
that has happened in 40 years. Now,
what's really amazing is this. So, this
is this is the RTX Spark laptop. This
is the desktop. So, this one's from MSI
Joseph. This one's yours. Okay. Look how
beautiful it is. This agent could run
24/7
meter free and you could download your
agent. You could raise your lobster in
here.
This is your clock. It's running all the
time. No meter anxiety. And it's sitting
here connected to your whole house,
connected to your laptop, connected to
your display, all the cameras, your your
dryer, your water cooler, your water
heater, your everything, whatever you
want, your security system, all
connected to this. And this becomes your
personal AI, your personal AI agent. And
it gets smarter and smarter and smarter
over time because today we have Neotron
3 Ultra. Tomorrow we have Neotron 4 and
then Neotron 5, Neotron 6. And we just
keep getting us smarter and smarter and
smarter. And meanwhile, this is sitting
at home helping you do things. If you
want to book a travel, no problem. And
if you
if you want an incredible system, this
is a DGX station for Windows.
compatible with Windows, runs everything
in Windows, and and it has 768
GB of memory. And so you could run a
trillion parameter model. This is
unbelievable. 20 pedaflops,
8 terabytes per second of memory
bandwidth, and this sits by your desk.
You basically if you're a developer of
large language models, you're a
developer of agents, having this sit by
your desk gives you all the compute you
need and then when you deploy it, you
put it into the cloud. Now there's
something that if you look at this and
think about this, something is happening
here.
Remember
15 20 years ago we used to have an idea
called a foam.
Today we have an idea called a PC.
Today when you think about your phone,
the one thing you don't do with it is
make phone calls.
You do just about everything else. And
so that phone means something very
different to you than a phone of the
past.
I am certain what's going to happen here
is that the PC 10 years from now and the
PC that you think about today a tool
whether you launch applications
click and type and this PC is going to
be completely different. Here's my
theory.
I can totally imagine just as every
house today has a home theater where
many houses have home theaters, big TVs,
lawnmowers,
dishwashers.
I could totally imagine that someday
there's actually an AI supercomput in
your house and it's running all of your
agents. that's running all of your
assistants and they're doing all kinds
of things for you all the time and you
have to have it in your house just like
you have a home theater in your house,
you have stereoss in your house, you
have game consoles in your house, you
would have assist AI agent computers
running in your house and these in time
becomes a lot more like R2-D2 to you. It
becomes more like C3PO to you than it
feels like a PC to you.
There is no question this reinvention of
the computer is as big of a deal as the
reinvention of the phone into what we
now know as the smartphone. And so this
is the beginning of that journey. This
is the beginning of a new line. And so
we have a roadmap for this. This is a
brand new product family for us. every
single generation of architecture, we
will have a desktop, a laptop, a
workstation, and then a desktop, a
laptop and workstation. And the thing
that I am just incredibly pleased,
incredibly honored is that 100% of the
world's PC industry has joined us to
reinvent the PC. A new line, a new
beginning. Thank you.
As you know,
aentic AI is just a digital robot.
It understands, it reasons, it plans,
and it acts and use tools.
Agented AI is going to run across all of
these computers and you've seen me talk
about each and every one of these over
time. We're working on human or robotics
computers, robotics computers of all
kinds. We're working on self-driving car
computers. We're working on satellites.
You have GeForce which is has tensor
cores. I just talked about a whole new
line of PCs.
agriculture equipment, manufacturing
equipment, heavy industry equipment will
all be agentic. You'll even have a
little agentic
helper for yourself.
Even your base stations, the radio
stations of the future are going to be
agentic.
understanding traffic and thinking about
how to coordinate with the other base
stations so that you could use as little
energy as possible increase the
utilization the efficiency of the
spectral efficiency and so everything
will run agents today Nvidia is largely
in the center but I am pretty certain
that there will be tens of billions
hundreds of billions over time of
agentic systems agentic computers that
are going to be running around the
world. The biggest problem is data.
In the case of language models, all the
English and all the language that we
have on the internet that we trained on
was from the perspective of us. We wrote
it and we're reading it. However, in
order to create a data for AI robotics,
it has to be in the perception, the
perspective of the robot. And most of
the world's video data is from a third
person, not first person. And so agentic
systems, robotic systems,
physical AI, the data is the hardest
problem. You've seen us move up this
ladder. We started with tea operations,
which is basically human demonstration.
This is no different than the big
breakthrough of reinforcement learning,
human feedback. This then we use
simulation. This is where omniverse
comes in. This is no different than
reinforcement learning ver verifiable
rewards. Okay. And so we use these
systems to bootstrap
the AI model, the physical AI model.
Eventually we're able to learn from
third per third person reproing it into
first person. And now eventually through
bootstrapping we have a world foundation
model that can understand the physical
world from any perspective you want.
Third third third person first person
outside in inside out doesn't matter.
This is a big breakthrough indeed. And
today we are announcing
Cosmos 3. Cosmos 3 is the frontier of
physical AI.
We are at the frontier with language
models. There are so many people working
on it. However, in physical AI, we are
absolutely the world's best. I am so
proud of the team for doing this. This
is the foundation model for all of your
work. Whenever you want to create a
robot, whenever you want to create a
factory robot or a robot that works in a
factory, any kind of robot that in that
involves physical world, you now have a
companion, a Cosmos 3 that can
understand and reason. It can generate,
it can simulate in the loop, it can even
be the policy itself. It is on the top
of leaderboards all over the all over
the world. I am incredibly proud of
Cosmos and today we're announcing Cosmos
3. Let's take a look.
>> The real world is infinite and
unpredictable.
Physical AI needs data, but real world
data is impossible to scale. For
physical AI, compute is data. This is
Cosmos, an open frontier omniodel for
physical AI built on a new mixture of
transformers architecture. Pixels,
action, sound, and language flow into
the auto reggressive transformer, which
reasons, plans, and instructs the
diffusion transformer, which generates
what comes next.
Developers post-train Cosmos across
embodiment and use cases. As a VLM,
Cosmos watches the physical world,
understands what's happening, describing
scenes, and flagging what matters.
As a world model, Cosmos generates
physics accurate synthetic video from an
image, text, or video.
As a simulator, Cosmos closes the loop
for policy training and evaluation. And
as the foundation of NVIDIA Omnidreams,
an action conditioned world model,
Cosmos predicts the future frame by
frame.
Post train Cosmos and it becomes a world
action model. Perceiving, reasoning,
planning, generating actions
for robots of every kind.
for everything that moves.
A new kind of data, a new kind of
teacher generated by computer.
Cosmos, the foundation for developers of
the age of physical AI.
It's takes data plus compute gives you
AI.
Now that we have AI,
compute is data. And so use Cosmos 3,
train a whole bunch of AI models. Cosmos
is such an incredible open model system.
It's exactly the same as Neotron. We
open the model, we open the data, and we
even opened how we trained it so that
you could enhance it for yourself and
turn Cosmos into your proprietary model.
We have such incredible partners working
with us in so many different industries.
Now the model itself is the most of
course the most understandable part of
the AI stack. But the AI stack is very
complicated. It has generators
the model simulators and the runtime
just as just as it is for agentic
systems. these cars or essentially a
physical AI a agentic robot that is a is
a autonomous vehicle has also this
complicated stack. Today we're
announcing Alpamo 2, an open model for
self-driving cars. We're working with
car companies across the world. If you
look at these brands that have signed up
for the Nvidia Hyperion that are
building Nvidia Hyperion cars, this
represents about 80%
of the world's cars. The manufacturers
represent 80% of the world's cars. We
are going to have a whole lot of Nvidia
Hyperion systems that are able to run
Alpha Mayo or anybody else's AV stack.
We are also connected into mobility
services. Approximately 97% of the
world's mobility services are connecting
with us. So that when we deploy Alpaio
on the Hyperion runtime with the Halos
operating system, we will be able to
connect to all of these services across
the world. Let's take a look at this.
>> Hey Mercedes, let's go to my favorite
sandwich shop.
>> Routing to your destination.
Lane is clear. Pulling out to start
drive. Nudge left due to the stationary
lead vehicle ahead blocking our lane.
Slow down to stop at the stop sign
controlling the intersection. Stop to
yield to the pedestrian since the person
is in our lane. Yield to the cut in
vehicle from the left. Nudge left to
clear the stopped vehicle blocking on
the right. Keep distance to the cut in
vehicle since it is emerging into our
lane. Nudge left due to the stopped van
crossing ahead. Stop to keep distance to
the lead vehicle. Keep distance directly
ahead in our lane. Keep distance to the
vehicle directly ahead in our lane. Stop
the stop sign since the intersection is
controlled. Stop the cross traffic.
Stop. Keep distance due to the truck
blocking the right side of our lane. Not
right due to the truck blocking the left
side of our lane. Left due to the
trucking side of our lane.
>> Your destination is on the right.
Alpao,
the world's first reasoning autonomous
vehicle.
If you let it talk all the time, it will
drive you crazy.
But we're very happy that it's talking
to itself all the time. That's called
thinking. And so, Alpamo is a reasoning
car. The technology that we've created
also applies to humanoids. Of course,
there are many new breakthroughs that
has to happen. The NVIDIA Isaac Groot is
our humanoid robotic stack model,
data generation,
simulation,
the runs, the runtime including the
operating system. This represents
group
platform, the Isaac group platform.
Every one of our systems, as you can
see, the exact same pattern. Whether
it's a gentic system for the cloud, a
gentic system for the PC, a robotic
system for a self-driving car, a robotic
system for a human or robot, all the
same. And of course, in every single
case, we build everything completely.
We build everything vertically
completely
integrated with code design, extreme
code design and then we open it up for
everybody to use whichever part you like
and whatever you want to use we even
help you modify. But the one thing that
is missing is we need a reference
platform for robotic systems. These
robotic systems are so complicated. So
many motors, so many sensors, so
fragile, and yet we need to have a way
to deliver these reference platforms.
Just like we do with PCs and DGXs and
clouds and self-driving cars, we now are
going to do it for robots. Today, we're
announcing the NVIDIA Isaac Group, a
reference humanoid robot, all fully
integrated. 25 degrees of freedom on the
on each hand made by Sharpa. 31 degrees
of freedom on the robot. 6 feet 150 lbs.
Just like me.
The first number is shorter. The second
number is bigger.
Otherwise, pretty close. and and this
platform runs the new Thor and our
entire software stack, data generation
stack, data simulation stack, the
runtime, all integrated into a robot
that is designed for everyone to use.
Now, we built this for higher education
and university researchers because for
them to build this is in insanely hard
to do. And so, let's take a look at
that.
The next leap in AI is generalpurpose
robots, humanoids. But building one is
hard. Every team starts from scratch,
stitching together simulators, teleyops
systems, data pipelines, and training
infrastructure. Months of setup before
research can start. NVIDIA Isaac Group,
an open development platform for
humanoid robots. Open models, simulation
and training libraries, and data
generators.
Plus the robot computer fully pipe clean
ready to go in hours. First set up the
simulation environment in Isaac lab.
Capture demonstrations with Isaac teleop
on a real or simulated robot.
Generate synthetic data with Omniverse
and Cosmos. Scaling one demonstration
into thousands.
Train policies. Evaluate them in Isaac
Lab Arena.
Deploy through Isaac Ross running on
jets and Thor.
Every element modular open. Use ours or
swap in your own.
Groot is powering robotics research
across every discipline for every domain
from research labs to factory floors.
One open platform
and now a new addition. Isaac Groot
reference design robots built on
NVIDIA's open platform ready for
frontier research for any lab anywhere.
The age of robotics starts here. Nvidia
Isaac Groot.
So many robots.
We're working with just about everybody
who's working on robots in the world or
robotic systems in world. Let me tell
you what I told you. The computer
industry has been completely changed
in the last six months. Everything
changed.
Everything changed because agents were
realized and it converged with the
latest frontier models and it made
possible the AI to now do useful work.
The computing pattern will repeat over
and over and over again. This computing
pattern of an agent that's a model, a
harness that uses tools with skills and
runs in a runtime. That runtime depends
on whether it's in the cloud or on prem
on a PC or in a robot. But the computing
pattern is exactly the same for all of
them. You will use different harnesses
because of your preference. You'll use
different models because of your
preference. You will improve them for
your proprietary use. You would create
sub super agents that you can rent to
other people to help them do their work.
This agentic platform, this agentic
pattern, Nvidia has an enterprise AI
toolkit. This is a wonderful way for all
of you to engage AIS and for us it's a
wonderful growth opportunity.
Vera Rubin is in full production
whereas Grace Blackwell was created to
process AI particularly inference. Vera
Rubin was created to run agents. It is
in full production. It is much much more
than a GPU. It is an entire disagregated
distributed agent processing system.
Nvidia has really become an
infrastructure company. Not just a GPU
company, not just a systems company, but
an infrastructure company to help you
generate the maximum revenues, the
maximum profit, and to get there as soon
as possible.
the agent world.
This new way of doing computing where
you build CPUs now for agents not for
people
CPUs for agents has its own special
requirement and our NVIDIA Vera is
revolutionary. I'm so happy about its
ramp the orders already. It's going to
make it the fastest and the most
successful product launch in our
company's history. Nvidia and Microsoft
has created a whole new line of PCs.
This is a new beginning. And of course,
that exact same agentic pattern that I
agentic processing pattern, computing
pattern that I just described is also
going to run on all kinds of devices. I
mentioned PCs, but in the future, it'll
be robots and satellites and base
stations and factories in the cloud, on
prim at the edge. This pattern, agentic
AI system, this agentic computing
pattern will be replicated in computers
all over. How we think about the
personal computer will very likely
change. I want to thank all of you for
your partnership, your friendship. We
couldn't be here without everything that
we do together. I am so proud of how
you've been so successful this last
year. The next year is going to be even
more. I have one more thing for you.
Let's take a look.
You ready to
>> Let's do this. The keynotes done at
Computex Jensen. Show the world what's
next. Useful AI has arrived. Agents
working by your side. But in case you
miss things we said today, we're going
to break it all down for you. Taipei.
Agents used to be misunderstood. Only
movie stars had them in Hollywood. Now
we all got teams making dreams come
true. Building companies from living
rooms, but they need so much comput. We
hear you. That's why we created Ver
>> Proven stole the show is true. The
cheapest tokens coming through
>> 10 times faster inference heaven more
special agent than 0007
>> blue field keeps agents memory true.
>> Now let's talk about it. CPU
>> 50% faster. That's outrageous.
>> Not for Ver.
>> It's built for agents. Envy link fusion
blends A6 smartly.
>> Everyone's welcome to the Envy Link
party. Well, if you like that
introduction
in full production
ultra leave the run 5x faster work gets
done keep the guard rails right open
shell keeps the sand tight
>> your code migrated and reviewed all
before this song is
a five layer cake
no mistake global AI cloud gaws keeps
power lean connecting
Every optimized for you
>> so you can have your cake
>> can eat it too.
>> RTX.
>> Biggest PC moment in 40 years.
>> Agents powering our workflow running
anywhere Windows go.
>> Harnesses run on CPU.
>> Models fly on GPU.
>> Cosmos worlds that robots need.
>> Turning computer into synthetic feet.
Alpha OC's and reasons through
>> understands roads like people do.
>> Food is how they learn to move.
>> Learning skills and finding growth is
powered by the future's human.
Oh, he sing. Oh,
he sing.
Oh, he don't sing.
The future's bright. Come see what's
next.
>> Thank you, Taiwan.
>> Welcome to Computex.
Have a great compex.
Thanks for an amazing year. Thank you
for all your friendship and support.
Thank you. Take care. Have a great
complex.
Woke up feeling something shift. Same
room but the air felt thick. Mirror said
I'm still that kid. I said you're bigger
than this.
Tie my laces shook. First step was the
hardest one. Every lap, every sideways
look when the races